Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS 208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group IV: Horsford Family
  - Series A: Eben N. Horsford
    - Subseries 8: Norumbega/Northmen Materials
      - Boston Public Library acknowledgment of donation, 1889 June 25 (Box 87, Folder 49)
      - American Antiquarian Society acknowledgment of donation, 1889 June 26 (Box 87, Folder 50)
      - The Chicago Public Library certificate of receipt of gift, 1889 July 17 (Box 87, Folder 51)
      - Yale University Library certificate of receipt of gift, 1889 July 19 (Box 87, Folder 52)
      - Harvard College Library acknowledgment of book gift, 1889 July 26 (Box 87, Folder 53)
      - Program - "Completing the Tower" re Norumbega, 1889 (Box 87, Folder 54)
      - The Discovery of the Ancient City of Norumbega by E.N. Horsford, 1889 (Box 87, Folder 55)
      - Library receipts for "The Problem of the Northmen", 1888-1890 (Box 87, Folder 56)
      - Review of the Problem of the Northmen and the Site of Norumbega by Professor Olson, reply by E.N. Horsford, 1890 (Box 87, Folder 57)
      - Seventeenth of May Festival, 1891 (Box 87, Folder 58)
      - File on origins of America 1 of 2, 1892, undated (Box 87, Folder 59)
      - File on origins of America 2 of 2, 1892, undated (Box 87, Folder 60)
      - The Story of Norumbega, undated (Box 87, Folder 61)
      - Scientific Notes re Norumbega, undated (Box 87, Folder 62)
      - Notes on the Landfall of John Rut in 1527 and other explorers, undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 1 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 2 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 3 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 4 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 5 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 6 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 7 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 8 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Writing tablet with notes and manuscripts re linguistics and Norumbega 9 of 9, undated (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - The Northmen in America, undated (Box 88, Folder 11)
      - Norumbega Notes, undated (Box 88, Folder 12)
      - Prospectus of the Pre-Columbian Discovery of America by the Northmen, undated (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Subseries 9: Travel and Events Materials
      - Invitations and tickets, 1845-1848 (Box 88, Folder 14)
        Retained in original order.
      - George M. Lane's ticket for admission to Mount Auburn Cemetery, 1865 May 29 (Box 88, Folder 15)
      - Theatrical programs, 1868, undated (Box 88, Folder 16)
      - Admissions ticket to the college yard, 1870 (Box 88, Folder 17)
      - S.S. Pierce & Co. price list for champagnes, 1873 November 24 (Box 88, Folder 18)
      - Programm fuer den Ausflug der International Jury, 1873 (Box 88, Folder 19)
      - Celebration of the 97th Anniversary of American Independence in Vienna, Austria, 1873 July 4 (Box 88, Folder 20)
      - Deutscher Naturforscher u. Aerzte, 1873 (Box 88, Folder 21)
      - Menu from Grand Hotel Hungaria in Budapest, 1873 July 27 (Box 88, Folder 22)
      - Calling card Dr. F. Migerka (Vienna Welt Altessuling), circa 1873 (Box 88, Folder 23)
      - Invitation to American independence Day Celebration (Vienna Exposition?), 1873 (Box 88, Folder 24)
      - Materials from 1873 Weltausstellung in Vienna (Box 88, Folder 25)
      - "Notice!!! The jury will visit...", 1873 (Box 88, Folder 26)
      - Ticket piece - Vienna Welt Ausstellung, 1873 (Box 88, Folder 27)
      - Dinner program - Hon. Marshall Jewell, U.S. Minister to Russia, 1873 (Box 88, Folder 28)
      - Reception of Dr. Gould, 1874 (Box 88, Folder 29)
      - Items re Bunker Hill Centennial Commemoration, 1875 (Box 88, Folder 30)
      - Tickets for admission to Machinery Building, 1876 October 18 (Box 88, Folder 31)
      - Railroad and steamer materials, 1880, undated (Box 88, Folder 32)
      - Concert programs, 1881 (Box 88, Folder 33)
      - Charles River Street Railway Company Printed Notice, 1882 (Box 88, Folder 34)
      - Pass and invitation to Las Vegas, Hot Springs, New Mexico from Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railroad Company, 1882 April 17 (Box 88, Folder 35)
      - Printed material re 1886 concert in Bergen, Norway organized by Alexander Bull (Box 88, Folder 36)
      - Eastern Yacht Club ticket, 1886 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - America's Cup tickets and program, 1887 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - City Hall Corner Stone Event Invitation, 1889 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Office of Water Board invitation, 1889 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - The Lincoln Art Society Programme, 1889-1890 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - Misc. unidentified tickets, undated (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - N.P. Banks ticket to "Members Gallery", undated (Box 89, Folder 7)
      - Map and timetables for Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railroad Company, undated (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - Trunk Line Passenger Committee Certificate Plan, undated (Box 89, Folder 9)
      - Cabinet map of the Denver and Rio Grande Railway, undated (Box 89, Folder 10)
      - Card describing "The Mammoth Steam Ship Great Eastern", undated (Box 89, Folder 11)
      - Long Island Railway Map, undated (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - Business card - The Marine Hotel, Isle of Wight, undated (Box 89, Folder 13)
      - Brochure - Restorative Hotel Fine-Hok, at Pompeii, undated (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Subseries 10: Newspapers and Magazines
      - The Cultivator, 1847 (Box 89, Folder 15)
      - The Southern Planter, Vol. XVI. No. 4, 1856 April (Box 89, Folder 16)
      - Newspaper clipping - "Prof. E.N.Horsford's Fire-Proof Safe", 1863 April 25 (Box 89, Folder 17)
      - Our Young Folks, No. 5, 1865 May (Box 89, Folder 18)
      - Clipping, "An Iron Clad at Sea", 1866 January 6 (Box 89, Folder 19)
      - Good Health "A Journal of Physical and Mental Culture", 1870 September (Box 89, Folder 20)
      - Newspaper clipping, "A Beautiful Incident", 1871 (Box 89, Folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (used as wrappers?), 1861, 1871, undated (Box 89, Folder 22)
        Oversize materials removed to Box 143 Folder 28 and Box 152 Folder 8.
      - The Boston Medical and Surgical Journal, 1873 September 11 (Box 89, Folder 23)
      - Newspaper clipping - "Harvard Class Day" and "Miss Horsford is Visiting This City", 1870s (Box 89, Folder 24)
      - Life, Vol. 1, No. 1, 1883 (Box 89, Folder 25)
      - Newspaper Clipping - The Bloomfield Citizen - "Letter from Boston", 1883 June 2 (Box 89, Folder 26)
      - The Geology of Long Island by F.J.H. Merrill, 1886 (Box 89, Folder 27)
      - Providence Journal Newsclipping "In a Gun Foundry - Casting the Big Mortar at the Builders Works Saturday", 1889 April 7 (Box 89, Folder 28)
      - Newspaper clipping - Globe "Prof. Horsford, who has gone to Europe, will joing his family...", 1890 August 10 (Box 89, Folder 29)
      - Newspaper clipping - "Fire Destroys Isaac Fiske House", 1890 August 27 (Box 89, Folder 30)
      - Newspaper clipping - Shelter Island Town Notes, undated (Box 89, Folder 31)
      - Newspaper clipping - Schenectady Union-Star Obituation and articles re Dr. E.C. Lawrence, undated (Box 89, Folder 32)
      - Newspaper clipping - "Shelter Island History - Bits of Romance that Cling to the Charming Spot", undated (Box 89, Folder 33)
      - Newspaper clipping - "Economic Arbitration", undated (Box 89, Folder 34)
      - Newspaper clipping about women's equality, undated (Box 89, Folder 35)
      - Newspaper clipping - "Pseudonyms of Prominent Literary Celebrities", undated (Box 89, Folder 36)
    - Subseries 11: Poetry and Miscellaneous Materials
      - Speech of William G. Dillingham in Favor of the Bill to Establish a School of Arts, 1838 (Box 89, Folder 37)
      - Notes of Walker's Arithmetic for Nathan Light, 1841 October 25 (Box 89, Folder 38)
      - Note about visiting Dr. Webster's office, 1849 December 8 (Box 89, Folder 39)
      - Trial of John W. Webster for the murder of George Parkman, 1850 (Box 89, Folder 40)
      - Printed speech of Hon. J. Horsford In Favor of the Establishment of an Agricultural Bureau, 1852 June 24 (Box 89, Folder 41)
      - Diagram of the Senate Chamber of the State of New York, 1856 (Box 89, Folder 42)
      - Worcester's Quarto Dictionary - proposal for library edition for subscribers, circa 1859 (Box 89, Folder 43)
      - Life insurance company pamphlets, 1858, 1861 (Box 89, Folder 44)
      - Pamphlets Engine Actuated by Heated Atmospheric Air, 1861 April 24 (Box 89, Folder 45)
      - "How George Newmark Sung his Hymn for the Church of Christ", 1865 (Box 89, Folder 46)
      - French Universal Exposition for 1867 - Official Correspondence (Box 89, Folder 47)
      - Commonwealth of Massachusetts - Second Annual Report of the Board of Harbor Commissioners, 1868 (Box 89, Folder 48)
      - Plan for Laying Out the Village of Oak Bluffs, Martha's Vineyard, 1870 (Box 89, Folder 49)
      - Selections from the Godly Prayers of Mr. Edward Dering, 1870 (Box 89, Folder 50)
      - Tide Tables for the Atlantic Coast of the United States for the Year 1873, 1872 (Box 89, Folder 51)
      - Poem - "Mamie's Birthday Lines", 1874 (Box 89, Folder 52)
      - A Practical Consideration of the Currency of the United States (Rumford Press), 1874 (Box 89, Folder 53)
      - Song - E.N. Horsford "On Shelter Island's Shore", 1874 (Box 89, Folder 54)
        Removed from folder of photographs "Portraits - Jedediah Horsford, unknowns, picture postcard from Eben H. Fiske in Nuermberg circa 1871, undated" Box 120 Folder 2.
      - Poem - H.W. Longfellow "From My Armchair", 1879 (Box 89, Folder 55)
      - "A Little Shut-In Hero" by Sarah Bradford, circa 1870s (Box 89, Folder 56)
      - Pamphlet for the Economic Electric Company, 1882 (Box 89, Folder 57)
      - Quarterly Report of the Western Union Telegraph Company, 1882 (Box 89, Folder 58)
      - Cook's Patent Cupola Wind-Mill, circa 1882 (Box 89, Folder 59)
      - Thanksgiving List, 1882 (Box 89, Folder 60)
      - Advertisement - Illustrated History of Suffolk County, circa 1882 (Box 89, Folder 61)
      - Flyer - A.J. Corcoran's Storm Defying Windmill, 1885 (Box 89, Folder 62)
      - Office of Parkinson and Burr; Bankers and Brokers [list of bonds?], 1885 (Box 89, Folder 63)
      - Petition & copies of letters re Fund for Ada Howard, 1885 (Box 89, Folder 64)
      - "Houghtaling's Hand-Book of Useful Information", 1886 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - "The Revolution, Washington and the Constitution" by Rev. Abraham Sylvester Gardiner, 1886 (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - A List of Patrons for the Egypt Exploration Fund, 1887 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Elizabeth Darrah - In Memoriam, 1887 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Notice from Dr. Charles Byrne, 1887 (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Lectures on Greek and Roman Antiquities, Catalogue of Annie S. Peck, 1888 (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous printed material, circa 1886-1888 (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - Pamphlet - "Henry Romeike's Press Cuttings", 1888 (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - Winifred Howell's death notice, 1889 (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - First Church in Cambridge Roll Call, 1889 (Box 90, Folder 10)
      - Silas Hamilton Douglas' death notice, 1890 (Box 90, Folder 11)
      - Dr. Heinrich Schwarz's death notice, 1890 (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - Elizabeth Thompson Science Fund Information, 1890 June (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - Stock certificate - Harvest Stove Company, 1890 (Box 90, Folder 14)
      - S.C. Griggs & Co. Ad - The Literature of Norseland, undated (Box 90, Folder 15)
      - Ad for Stray Songs of Life, Poems of D.B. Duffield with excerpt, 1889 (Box 90, Folder 16)
      - Reports - The Committee on Political Reform, 1891 (Box 90, Folder 17)
      - Newspaper clippings - "In the Library" by Anne C.L. Botta, "Life's Sculpture", 1891, undated (Box 90, Folder 18)
      - E.N. Horsford Poem, undated (Box 90, Folder 19)
      - Pamphlet - New Year's Note, undated (Box 90, Folder 20)
      - "Seize This Very Minute" Poem, undated (Box 90, Folder 21)
      - Latin Poem - "Francisci Jacobi Child", undated (Box 90, Folder 22)
      - Poem - "True Love", undated (Box 90, Folder 23)
      - Poem - "A Voice from Heaven", undated (Box 90, Folder 24)
      - E.N. Horsford Poem - "Bright [Oer] Thy Path Shall Shine the Rays of Fame", undated (Box 90, Folder 25)
      - Poem - "To the Memory of the Dead" by Isaac Watts, undated (Box 90, Folder 26)
      - Poem - "There is No Destiny of Fate" by Ella Wheeler Wilcox, undated (Box 90, Folder 27)
      - Poem - "Banished from Massachusetts, 1660, on a Painting by E.A. Abbey" by John Greenleaf Whittier, undated (Box 90, Folder 28)
      - Poem by Sidney Smith "For a Christmas Salad..." Mounted on Ad for Wedding Invitations, Visiting Cards, undated (Box 90, Folder 29)
      - J.C. Hall & Co. Bookmark/Blotter, undated (Box 90, Folder 30)
      - Ad - A Guerin Importer, undated (Box 90, Folder 31)
      - Circular - Briggs & Huntington Ad for Fire-Proof Safes, undated (Box 90, Folder 32)
      - Ad - Boston Electric Company, undated (Box 90, Folder 33)
      - Map of Ridley Park by Landscape Gardener Robert Morris Copeland, undated (Box 90, Folder 34)
      - Pamphlet/Ad - Boston & Manufacturing Co., undated (Box 90, Folder 35)
      - Ad for Norwegian Novel - The Happy Boy, undated (Box 90, Folder 36)
      - Peters' Musical Monthly - Subscription Advertisement, undated (Box 90, Folder 37)
      - The Star-Spangled Banner, undated (Box 90, Folder 38)
      - Libraries and Catalogues - Miss Mary Bates Merriam, undated (Box 90, Folder 39)
      - Pamphlet - "University Education for Women", undated (Box 90, Folder 40)
      - Blank postcards, undated (Box 90, Folder 41)
      - Henry F. Durant: "A Few Thoughts on the Study of the Bible", undated (Box 90, Folder 42)
      - Santa Claus' Annual Greeting - C.B. Moore and Co., undated (Box 90, Folder 43)
      - Removal Notice - Bureua of Social Requirements, undated (Box 90, Folder 44)
      - Maps Showing Napoleon's Invasion of Russia, undated (Box 90, Folder 45)
      - The Blackstone Canal by Brenton H. Dickson, undated (Box 90, Folder 46)
      - "It Was a Lover and His Lass" [fragment], undated (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - "A Feudal Court of To-Day", undated (Box 90, Folder 48)
      - Part of New York form, undated (Box 90, Folder 49)
      - Scrap of printed material - possibly re Lion Gardiner, undated (Box 90, Folder 50)
      - Pamphlet - "Guide to 19th C. Authors" by Louise M. Hodgkins, undated (Box 90, Folder 51)
      - Neatness, undated (Box 90, Folder 52)
      - "Making the U.S. Map" by H.G. Cutler, undated (Box 90, Folder 53)
      - Journal with list of monarchs from various European kingdoms, undated (Box 90, Folder 54)
      - "Quoted by Rosenthal", undated (Box 90, Folder 55)
      - Humbugs originally written for American Magazine, undated (Box 90, Folder 56)
      - Prescription instructions, undated (Box 90, Folder 57)
      - Translation terms, undated (Box 90, Folder 58)
      - Typed page with quote from S.S. Cox and Wordsworth verse, undated (Box 90, Folder 59)
      - Fragment [address?], undated (Box 90, Folder 60)
      - Legal notes - Edson H. Chace v David A. Chadin et al, undated (Box 90, Folder 61)
      - Printed hymn lyrics, undated (Box 90, Folder 62)
      - Instructions for Keasley and Mattison's Effervescing Citrate of Lithia, undated (Box 90, Folder 63)
      - "A Poem for the Columbians" by Herbert Constantine Livingstone, undated (Box 90, Folder 64)
      - Note and two addresses, undated (Box 90, Folder 65)
      - Auction notes, undated (Box 90, Folder 66)
      - "Diet List", undated (Box 90, Folder 67)
      - Nanette Sire Chart (horses), undated (Box 90, Folder 68)
      - "List of things to be sent home" (written by one of E.N.'s siblings), undated (Box 90, Folder 69)
      - Published financial account tables (German), undated (Box 90, Folder 70)
      - Nellie's Precious Gifts (E.N.H.), undated (Box 90, Folder 71)
      - German wax seals, undated (Box 90, Folder 72)
  - Series B: Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford
    Mary Gardiner Horsford (1824-1855) was raised on Shelter Island, but later attended school in Albany, New York at the Albany Female Academy, where she met E.N. Horsford. She was a poet and had several works published in newspapers, and had a volume of her work entitled Indian Legends and Other Works published in 1855.
    This series contains correspondence and a small volume of manuscripts, mostly poetry.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - "Cousin Abby", September 3, 1846 (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Ana, 1843 April 2 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - Mary B, undated (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Grace Chapell, undated (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - Cherie (?), undated (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - Eliza, undated (Box 91, Folder 6)
      - Mary Ann Fosdick, 1815 (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - S.L.G., August 19, 1845 (Box 91, Folder 8)
      - Phoebe Gardiner, 1847-1849, undated (Box 91, Folder 9)
      - Phoebe Gardiner, 1847-1848, undated (Box 91, Folder 10)
      - Samuel Gardiner, 1838-1850 (Box 91, Folder 11)
      - to Samuel S. Gardiner, 1853 (Box 91, Folder 12)
      - Helen (cousin), undated (Box 91, Folder 13)
      - Envelopes - E.N. Horsford to Samuel Gardiner and Mary Gardiner (Horsford), undated (Box 91, Folder 14)
      - Julia (?), undated (Box 91, Folder 15)
      - Fanny Gardiner Lane (sister), 1848 (Box 91, Folder 16)
      - Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu, undated (Box 91, Folder 17)
      - Lizzie, 1844-1846, undated (Box 91, Folder 18)
      - Lucie, undated (Box 91, Folder 19)
      - Maria, 1843 (Box 91, Folder 20)
      - A.M. Meys, undated (Box 91, Folder 21)
      - Gracie Sutherland, September 6, 1844 (Box 91, Folder 22)
      - Pierre Van Wyck - invitation, June 25, 1815 (Box 91, Folder 23)
      - M. Waterman, 1846, undated (Box 91, Folder 24)
      - A.D. Woodbridge 1 of 4, 1841-1844 (Box 91, Folder 25)
      - A.D. Woodbridge 2 of 4, 1845-1847 (Box 91, Folder 26)
      - A.D. Woodbridge 1 of 2, undated (Box 91, Folder 27)
      - A.D. Woodbridge 2 of 2, undated (Box 91, Folder 28)
      - Envelopes to Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner [Horsford], Phoebe Gardiner [Horsford], undated (Box 91, Folder 29)
      - Unknown, undated (Box 91, Folder 30)
    - Subseries 2: Manuscripts and Other Materials
      - Advice to a Young Christian on the Importance of Aiming at an Elevated Standard of Piety, 1830 (Box 91, Folder 31)
      - Bible belonging to Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford, 1834 (Box 91, Folder 32)
      - "Written on Miss H's Slate", 1840 September (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - Poems - Mary L'H. Gardiner [Horsford], 1843, undated (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - National Birth Night Assembly invitation to Miss Gardiner (M.L'H.G.), 1845 (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - Poem - to Mary from Valentine, February 14, 1847 (Box 92, Folder 4)
      - Small Diary - Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford, 1848 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      - Poems by Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford, 1843, 1849, undated (Box 92, Folder 6)
      - Poem - "My Sister" by Mary Gardiner, undated (Box 92, Folder 7)
      - Poetry manuscripts from Indian Legends and Other Poems, undated (Box 92, Folder 8)
      - Printing proofs with edits for Indian Legends and Other Poems by Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford, undated (Box 92, Folder 9)
      - Young men's Association - 106th Anniversary of American Independence, undated (Box 92, Folder 10)
      - A Parody of Miss Gardiner's Communion Hymn by Herbert Livingston, undated (Box 92, Folder 11)
      - Madeline poem, undated (Box 92, Folder 12)
      - Poem - "A Prophesy - to Mary" by Edward, undated (Bin 92, Folder 13)
      - Poem - "The First Department" by Eliza Mirduey (?), undated (Box 92, Folder 14)
      - Poem - from "Gardiner Financial Documents - 1813", undated (Box 92, Folder 15)
      - Poem - "Life's Light and Shade", undated (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - Series C: Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford
    Phoebe Gardiner Horsford (1826-1903) also attended Albany Female Academy. She married E.N. Horsford in 1857 following the death of her sister Mary.
    This series contains Phoebe’s correspondence, materials related to the maintenance of the family’s affairs following the death of E.N. Horsford, and a small number of manuscripts.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Alea, 1884 June 2 (Box 92, Folder 17)
      - American Loan & Trust Company, 1886 (Box 92, Folder 18)
      - N.D. Arnold, 1898 (Box 92, Folder 19)
      - to Mr. Arnold, 1896, 1898 (Box 92, Folder 20)
      - George Barleu, 1884 (Box 92, Folder 21)
      - C.H. Bateman, 1895 (Box 92, Folder 22)
      - Nellie Bean, 1894 (Box 92, Folder 23)
      - "Biddie", 1886, 1887, undated (Box 92, Folder 24)
      - Bigelow Mennard and Co., 1884 July 5 (Box 92, Folder 25)
      - Edwina Booth, 1884 July 30 (Box 92, Folder 26)
      - Alice L. Van Brunt, 1885 September 20 (Box 92, Folder 27)
      - Henry Van Brunt, 1884 August 26 (Box 92, Folder 28)
      - Sara Buel, 1876, 1884-1886 (Box 92, Folder 29)
      - Mabie L. Burneld, 1886 August 12 (Box 92, Folder 30)
      - Maria Byam, 1893 (Box 92, Folder 31)
      - W.E. Byerly, 1884 (Box 92, Folder 32)
      - E.N.C., 1891 August 26, undated (Box 92, Folder 33)
      - George Calmer[?], 1886 September 14 (Box 92, Folder 34)
      - Mary L. Coe, 1885 August 11 (Box 92, Folder 35)
      - Davis Collamore and Co., 1887 July 19 (Box 92, Folder 36)
      - Allen Curtis, undated (Box 92, Folder 37)
      - Benjamin R. Curtis (grandson), undated (Box 92, Folder 38)
      - Helena Curtis, 1887, undated (Box 92, Folder 39)
      - Mary G. Curtis (granddaughter), undated (Box 92, Folder 40)
      - Minne W. Curtis, 1895 (Box 92, Folder 41)
      - Mrs. A.W. Cutler, 1893 (Box 92, Folder 42)
      - Edith L. Dana, 1884, 1891 (Box 92, Folder 43)
      - Richard H. Dana, 1891 August 1 (Box 92, Folder 44)
      - James Day, 1886 July 31 (Box 92, Folder 45)
      - H.W. Deane, undated (Box 92, Folder 46)
      - Frances Dering, 1884 (Box 92, Folder 47)
      - R.G. Duvall, 1895 September 16 (Box 92, Folder 48)
      - Louis Dyer, 1884-1886 (Box 92, Folder 49)
      - Edith (niece), 1885 July 31 (Box 92, Folder 50)
      - Carrie B. Eustis, 1885 August 3 (Box 92, Folder 51)
      - Sadie E. Eustis, 1884 August 7 (Box 92, Folder 52)
      - Mary Felton, undated (Box 92, Folder 53)
      - Fannie Washington Finch, 1885 June 2 (Box 92, Folder 54)
      - Andrew Fiske, 1886, 1887, 1891 (Box 92, Folder 55)
      - Gardiner Fiske, 1899 September 6 (Box 92, Folder 56)
      - Mary E. Ford, 1895 April 13 (Box 92, Folder 57)
      - A.E. Freeman, 1886 August 10 (Box 92, Folder 58)
      - M.L.G.[?], 1887 August 8 (Box 92, Folder 59)
      - Gerhard Gade [to PGH?], undated (Box 92, Folder 60)
      - Coralie L. Gardiner, undated (Box 92, Folder 61)
      - Fannie E. Gardiner, 1853, undated (Box 92, Folder 62)
      - Samuel Gardiner, 1849-1850 (Box 92, Folder 63)
      - W.W. Gardiner, 1886 September 15 (Box 92, Folder 64)
      - George and Mary (nephew and niece), undated (Box 92, Folder 65)
      - Benj. Ires Gilman, 1884 July 23 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - Clarrie T. Gladwin, 1896 November 29 (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - Ellen A. Gordwin, 1886 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      - B.A. Gould, 1886 July 11 (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - Catherine Gower, 1886 August (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - Asa Gray, undated (Box 93, Folder 6)